#### Contact

hariprasadpai@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/paihari (LinkedIn) github.com/paihari (Other) dev.to/paihari/ (Blog) simplificare.ch (Blog)

### Top Skills

Business Requirements
Project Management
Software Development

## Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
German (Limited Working)

#### Certifications

Goethe-Zertifikat A2 Deutsch

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Certified Multicloud Architect Associate

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Al Certified Foundations Associate

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Certified Security Professional

#### **Publications**

Distributed Ledger Technology Principles for Industry-Wide Acceptance

## Hariprasad Bantwal

Cloud Architect | Regulatory and Compliance | Financial Services | Infrastructure Operations | Engineering Management | Al Agent Engineering

Zürich Metropolitan Area

## Summary

With over 20 years of experience in Information Systems strategy, architecture, and cloud infrastructure, I specialize in aligning technology solutions with business goals to drive operational efficiency and transformation. My expertise spans cloud strategy, platform services, and engineering leadership for global organizations.

#### Key Strengths:

# Cloud Strategy & Infrastructure (Multi-Cloud, Hybrid Cloud, Self-Service Platforms)

# Strategic IS Alignment with Business Goals

# People Leadership across Global Teams

# Stakeholder Management with C-Suite & External Partners

# Regulatory Compliance & Governance Expertise

I thrive in collaborative environments where innovation, curiosity, and excellence come together to create sustainable, business-driven solutions using simple intelligence and AI.

#### Based in Zurich

Let's connect to drive impactful digital transformation and cloud excellence.

## Experience

#### Freelance

Cloud/Al Strategy - Consultant/Architect July 2024 - Present (1 year 1 month) Zurich, Switzerland

• Incubated SyntropAI, a systemic AI framework for autonomous, policy-driven multicloud orchestration.

- Designed and built the Al Cloud Hub architecture, integrating Executive, Legislative, and Regulatory layers via the Model Context Protocol (MCP).
- Engineered intelligent agents to operate across AWS, Azure, and OCI, enabling secure, compliant provisioning with human-in-the-loop governance.
- Pioneered graph-based memory, FinOps integration, and explainable automation to deliver scalable, audit-ready cloud infrastructure with NIST OSCAL-Formatted Security Compliance SSP CISO Reports

#### Avalog

Cloud Architect/Sr. Project Manager, Cloud and Infrastructure January 2020 - May 2024 (4 years 5 months)

Zurich, Switzerland

- Led the Cloud Blueprint initiative, integrating strategy, architecture, and security, which improved operational efficiency by 30%.
- Standardized cloud infrastructure processes across multiple platforms, reducing operational costs by 40%.
- Developed and implemented a Virtual Data Center strategy, optimizing workload provisioning in hybrid and multi-cloud environments.
- Guided the design and deployment of a Cloud Automation Orchestrator, enhancing scalability and real-time resource management.
- In the role of Project Manager successfully spearheaded the private cloud migration for 25 Swiss banks, ensuring near-zero downtime and maintaining high data integrity.

#### Credit Suisse

Technical Architect/FX OTC Capital Markets/Payments November 2010 - December 2019 (9 years 2 months)

Zürich Area, Switzerland

- Led the architecture and engineering for Forex and OTC settlements, enhancing transaction processing efficiency by 20%.
- Ensured platform compliance with FINMA, EMIR, and MiFID II regulations, aligning technology with business strategy.
- Designed a digital Confirmation Platform for OTC/Cash Products, which improved regulatory compliance and legal efficiency by 150%.
- Managed the Target IT Model for FX/OTC Settlement, aligning IT lifecycle management with business objectives.
- Proposed and implemented a platform renovation, replacing legacy systems with a responsive UX, improving user experience and operational efficiency.

- Served as IT Owner and Lead Architect for critical initiatives within Credit Suisse's high-volume payments platform, including pilot ISO 20022 integration with Supplier platform and cross-border payment processing at Poland.

Global Supply Chain Finance Ltd System Architect/Engineer September 2008 - October 2010 (2 years 2 months) Zug, Switzerland

- Led the migration of a flagship product to an open-source distributed platform, reducing time to market and total cost of ownership by 30% and improving scalability.
- Took technical ownership from initiation to rollout, ensuring seamless implementation by coordinating with legacy systems and Fortune 500 teams.
- Evaluated technologies and established high-level architecture and coding standards, enhancing development efficiency.
- Managed component design and data modeling, integrating with SWIFT and EDI standards to enhance system functionality.
- Implemented system monitoring and logging, providing training and documentation to support teams for smooth operation.

# Wipro Limited Portfolio Manager/Tech Lead: Credit Suisse, Zurich May 2004 - September 2008 (4 years 5 months) Zurich

- Served as the primary point of contact for IT vendor relationships, managing project delivery for the Payments Department, which handled 3 million transactions daily.
- Created and led the Core Team for Credit Suisse, managing a \$5 million budget and significantly improving project delivery and operational efficiency.
- Engaged with senior stakeholders, providing strategic updates and proposing innovative sourcing models to support future initiatives.
- Directed and mentored the onsite team, ensuring high-quality outcomes in project analysis, design, engineering, and delivery.
- Collaborated with the Pre-Sales department on proposals, contributing to business growth and enhancing client satisfaction.

Multitech/Universal/Goa Interlink Software Engineer 2001 - 2004 (3 years) Bengaluru Area, India

## Education

University of Mysore BE, Mechanical · (1996 - 2000)